centralpacificbank.com 2008-05-17

# Central Pacific Bank - Privacy Policy

##   
Privacy Policy

At Central Pacific Financial Corp., and our affiliated companies, we are very concerned about customer confidentiality and privacy*. Our employees treat the information we have concerning individual customers** in the same responsible, confidential way that we want our own financial affairs treated. We want you to be informed of our commitment to protect the privacy of your personal financial information with the following privacy principles***: 

## Collecting Information

We collect and retain customer information to give you better service, offer you more convenience, and to help you learn more about products and services that may be of interest to you. Customer information may be collected from a variety of sources, such as the following: 

  * **Application Information.** Information we receive from you on applications or other loan and account forms, such as your income and accounts; 
  * **Transaction and Experience Information.** Information about your transactions with us and our affiliates; 
  * **Consumer Report Information.** Information we receive from a consumer report, such as your credit history or creditworthiness; and 
  * **Information From Outside Sources.** Information from outside sources with your consent. 

*In this Consumer Privacy Policy, we refer to all Central Pacific Financial Corp. affiliated companies collectively as “Central Pacific Financial Corp.,” and we refer to any one company within Central Pacific Financial Corp. as an “Affiliate.”

**This Privacy Policy applies only to consumer customers, that is individuals who obtain financial products or services primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.

***This Privacy Policy applies to those companies in Central Pacific Financial Corp. that offer consumer products and services. These companies include Central Pacific Bank and Central Pacific HomeLoans, Inc., which we refer to collectively as “we,” “us,” or “our.”

## What Information We Disclose

**A. Within Central Pacific Financial Corp.**  
The Central Pacific Financial Corp. corporate family is made up of companies providing financial and other services, including Central Pacific Bank (CPB), Central Pacific HomeLoans, Inc., a mortgage broker, and others. We may share the customer information we collect described in the “Collecting Information” section with Affiliates. By sharing information with Affiliates, we hope to better serve your financial needs.

**B. With Outside Companies**  
We may share the customer information we collect described in the “Collecting Information” section, but only to the extent permitted by law with the following types of companies outside Central Pacific Financial Corp.: 

  * Financial service providers selected to provide our customers with specialized financial services, such as securities broker dealers or insurance companies. We disclose information only when we believe that this information is needed to offer you the product or service. You may choose to opt-out of this type of sharing (other than sharing permitted by law) by replying as instructed in the **How to Opt-out of Having Information** **Disclosed** section of this disclosure.   

  * Companies that work for us, such as companies that provide you products and services that you’ve requested or already have with us. These companies may include check printers and companies that prepare or mail account statements. In addition, we may share customer information with companies that work for us to provide marketing and other services or other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. 

**  
C.Information Disclosed to Outside Companies that Work for Us**  
We may share some or all of the customer information we collect described in the “Collecting Information” section, with companies that work for us for the purposes of servicing your account or performing marketing or similar services on our behalf or to financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. These companies are subject to contractual confidentiality provisions and may use the customer information we share only to provide the services we ask them to perform for you and us.

**D.Disclosing Information in Other Situations**  
We may also disclose certain customer information to government entities, credit bureaus and similar organizations, and otherwise as permitted by law. For example, customer information may be disclosed in connection with a subpoena or similar legal process, a fraud investigation, the recording of a mortgage in public records, or to provide information with your consent.

**E. Credit Bureau Information**  
In the regular course of business, Central Pacific Financial Corp. provides information to and obtains information from reputable credit reporting agencies in accordance with applicable laws and regulations. **If you believe that any of our Affiliates may have reported inaccurate information about any of your accounts to a consumer reporting agency please contact us at (808) 544-0500 (on Oahu), or 1-800-342-8422 (Neighbor islands, Continental U.S., Guam, Saipan, or Canada.)** We may report information about your accounts to credit bureaus. Late payments, missed payments, or other defaults on your account may be reflected in your credit report.

## How To Opt-out of Having Information Disclosed

By making customer information available to Affiliates within Central Pacific Financial Corp. and carefully selected outside companies, we are able to provide better service and offer financial services and products we believe you will value.

**Opt-out Selections:**

 **Selection # 1:** I do not wish to have the following information shared with other companies in Central Pacific Financial Corp.’s corporate family: 

  * Information from my applications to be used to determine my eligibility, such as my income.
  * Information from credit reports, such as my credit history.
  * Information from sources used to verify information I provide to you, such as outstanding loans or employment history. 

If you elect opt-out selection #1, please be aware that we may share other types of information within our corporate family. For example, we may share name and address, information about transactions or balances with us, as well as survey results.

**Selection # 2:** I do not wish to have my personal information shared with any entity outside of Central Pacific Financial Corp.’s corporate family except as permitted by law.

You may contact us to provide or change your privacy selections as stated above, by:

  * Calling us at: (808) 544-0500 (on Oahu), or   
                     1-800-342-8422 (Neighbor islands, Continental U.S., Guam, Saipan, or Canada.)  

  * Writing us at: Central Pacific Financial Corp.  
                      Centralized Branch Operations Department  
                      P.O. Box 3590  
                      Honolulu, HI 96811

If you have already provided an opt-out to us, you need not opt-out again. Your prior opt-out remains in effect until revoked in writing.

If you have a joint account, we will treat an opt-out direction by any account owner as applying to the entire account.

## Our Policies on the Collection and Use of Information on Former Customers

If you decide to close your account(s) or become an inactive customer, we will continue to adhere to the privacy policies and practices described in this notice.

## Our Security Procedures

We also take steps to safeguard customer information. We restrict access to your personal and account information to those employees who need to know that information to provide products or services to you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal standards to guard your nonpublic personal information.  

## Medical Information

You may sometimes provide medical information to us as part of an application for insurance. We do not share medical information among our family of companies or with third parties except to those who require access to this information in order to process the application. **We will not obtain, use, re-disclose or share – internally or externally – personal identifiable medical information in determining credit eligibility except as allowed by law, as disclosed to you when the information is collected, or when you consent.** Medical information (such as information related to your past, present, or future physical or mental health or condition) or the provision or payment of such healthcare services obtained as part of an application for insurance is shared only with those who require access to this information in order to process the application. 

## Disclosing Our Privacy Commitment To You

We want you to understand our commitment to personal privacy and have formulated this privacy policy. This privacy policy is provided to: 

  * a potential customer who inquires about our products and services or who would like a copy of our privacy policy 
  * a customer who has established a relationship with us. (The privacy policy is provided at the time the relationship is established, and annually thereafter.) 
  * a potential customer who has applied for a loan 
  * a visitor to our web site 

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy policy, please [contact us](http://www.centralpacificbank.com/contact/default.asp) or write to us at PO Box 3590, Honolulu, HI 96811, Attention: Centralized Branch Operations Department. 

## Internet Privacy On CPB's Web Site

For each visitor to CPB’s web site ([www.centralpacificbank.com](http://www.centralpacificbank.com/)) we automatically recognize the following visitor information: 

  * A visitor’s Internet Service Provider (for example, America Online or GST Hawaii Online), but not your specific e-mail address. For example, if your e-mail address is “SamSmith@GTE.net,” only the “GTE.net” part of the address is recognized. 
  * Aggregate visitor information on pages which customers visit. 

## Other Information About Our Web Site

  * **Children visiting CPB’s web site.** We are confident that parents will not judge any of the information provided by CPB as objectionable for viewing by their children. 
  * **Customers using CPB’s Internet Banking Service.** For customers using CPB Internet Banking, all visitor information is collected along with any information that you volunteer as a customer while using CPB’s web site. 
  * **Links to, or from, CPB’s web site.** CPB is not responsible for information practices employed by websites linked with our web site. Generally, links to non-CPB web sites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to users of CPB’s web site. 
  * **Encrypted information.** Information provided on CPB’s web site is encrypted or scrambled in order to secure information. 

This privacy policy may change from time to time.  
You may obtain the most current copy at CPB branches or visit the web site.

Effective Date  
This privacy policy is effective as of September, 2005.
